Guide to the Central Washington University Faculty Papers, Sarah Spurgeon Scrapbook 1946-1983 (bulk 1954-1956)
Central Washington University Archives and Special Collections
Central Washington University Faculty Papers, Sarah Spurgeon Scrapbook
1946-1983 (bulk 1954-1956)
Central Washington University, Archives and Special Collections 400 E University Way Ellensburg, WA 98926 (509) 963-1717 http://www.lib.cwu.edu/Archives-Special-Collections archive@cwu.edu
FP-0031
Spurgeon, Sarah
1.5 cubic feet 1 oversized box, 1 letter-sized Hollinger box Photographs, notebooks, and newspaper clippings in good condition
This collection contains photographs and newspapers relating to the work of Sarah Spurgeon, professor in the Art Department of Central Washington University (previously Central Washington College of Education and Central Washington State College) in the 1930s-1970s.
Biographical Note
Sarah Spurgeon (1903-1985) came to Ellensburg from Iowa in 1939 and joined the art department at the college the same year. She took a hiatus from her work at Central Washington College of Education during World War II when she went to work for Boeing as an artist. Following the war, she returned to Ellensburg and continued as a professor until her retirement in 1971. The Sarah Spurgeon Art Gallery, named in 1977 and currently housed in Randall Hall, is free and open to the public.
This collection consists of notebooks, scrapbooks, notices, and black-and-white photographs relating to the work of Sarah Spurgeon, professor in the Art Department of Central Washington College of Education (now Central Washington University) in the 1930s-1970s. Also included are several local newspaper clippings about art events in which Spurgeon or her students played a part.
Central Washington University began as the Washington State Normal School in 1891. In 1937, the school was rechristened the Central Washington College of Education. In 1961, the school became Central Washington State College and, finally, in 1977, Central Washington University.
Arranged by exhibit and material type
Open to the public
Further information about the Sarah Spurgeon Art Gallery is available here.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Spurgeon, Sarah
Central Washington University
Ellensburg, Wash.
Art--20th century; Education--United State
Colleges and Universities; Washington (State)
Photographic prints; Scrapbooks
Art teachers
- Photographs
  The following entails an inventory of captioned photographs in the Sarah Spurgeon Scrapbook.
  - Wenatchee Art Club visit to CWCE, Mr. and Mrs. Cleveland, Mrs. Barnum, Bob Mattielli, March 29, 1955
  - Ginkgo, 1955
  - Beaux Arts Ball, John Morgan, Peg Orr, 1956
  - Ginkgo Mural
  - Stan Day, Charles Smith, publicity for Larson Gallery Exhibit, Fall 1955
  - Art 100, Crayon Resist, 1956
  - Art Festival, Richard Rasmussen Gallery Talk, 1956
  - Figure Class visits nursery school, Spring 1955
  - Loren Sparks, Dorothy Dean, Sam Mohler, Helen Michaelson, Larry Moe
  - Betty Seresun, Senior Exhibit, 1956
  - Art Festival, 1956
  - Vantage
  - Lynn Williams, 1955
  - Hal Chambers and B. Barlow painting Boy Scout Jamboree mural. Materials paid for by Rotary Club of Ellensburg, Washington, 1946
  - Homecoming, Ann Nachetelo, Terry Randall, Sally Farmer, Judy Bower, Jim Kemp
  - H.S. Art Festival, 1955
  - Ann Nachatelo, Pat, Terry Randall, Sally Farmer, Judy Bower, Jim Kemp, 1958
  - Jim Jacobs, Rudy Kovaceuich, Ken Vertz, Gary Brown, Websters, 1953
  - Joan Stevens and Nancie Dunn, June 1958
  - 19 x 6 Art 100, Framing, John Hooper and Sagara
  - Homecoming Alumni Art Exhibit, 1953
  - Nancy Stevens, 1955
  - CES Library Tile Designed by Sarah Spurgeon, 1939, Miss Helen Librarian, 1954, 1939-1954
  - Bellevue Fair, 1954
  - Rudy Kovaceuich, Jim Jacobs, Ken Vertz, Gary Brown, 1953, Dec., Websters, Paintings by Helen Rhine, Joan Heppel, Jan Michelotti, Spring 1953
  - Jim Blanchard, Jane Simmons, Bellevue Fair, 1954
  - Tom Knudsen, Pat Cosper, Ted Olson, For article on Art Dept., B. Wiley Photo, December 1953
  - Boeing Flying Fortress
  - Wayerty, Joan Stevens, Delores Schiffner, Barney Flora, Peg Orr, Keep Washington Green Poster, Winter 1955
  - Jerry Dudley, Roger Assestine, Nursery School, CES, Spring 1955
  - Figure Class working on portraits for the play Harvey, Joan Heikell, Pat Haberman, Jeanne Stafford, Jerry Ward, Kathy Arivoldt, February 22, 1955
  - Art Festival, Spring 1958
  - Gary Brown, Nancy Stevens, YMCA, Spring 1955
- Newspaper Clippings
  - “Muralist Pictures the Ages-Old Ginkgo”
  - “Valley Artists Represented in Seattle Gallery Showing”
  - “Unveiling of Memorial Panels Completes Pool”
  - “CWC Delegation Draws Crowds at Fair in Bellevue”
  - “Annual East Side Exhibition Opens”
  - “Carry Out Bellevue Fair Theme”
  - “Memorial Plaques Placed”
  - “Bellevue Art, Craft Show Attracts Many”
- Scrapbook, "Notes on the Land"
  - Notebook for "Notes on the Land"
  - Miscellaneous
  - Spurgeon Gallery Exhibit Notices, 1980-1984
  - Local activism
  - Spurgeon Gallery Dedication, Letters, October 1977
  - Spurgeon Gallery Dedication, Photographs, October 1977
  - News clippings
  - Display materials